Mutants. Since the discovery of their existence...
自从变种人诞生以来
they have been regarded with fear...
就一直被投以恐惧
suspicion, often hatred.
怀疑、憎恶的目光
Across the planet, debate rages.
且不谈我们这个星球上的激烈争论
Are mutants the next link in the evolutionary chain...
变种人会成为 进化之路的一个新起点吗？
or simply a new species of humanity...
抑或成为同样为了生存而挣扎的
fighting for their share of the world?
又一种人类？
Eitherway, it is an historical fact:
无论如何，这都具有重大的历史意义
Sharing the world has never been humanity's defining attribute.
和其它物种分享生存权 从来就不是人类的特色
《X战警2》
"We are not enemies, but friends.
“我们是朋友，不是敌人”
"We must not be enemies.
“我们决不能兄弟阋墙”
"Though passion may have strained...
“激情或许会一时枯竭”
it must not break the bonds of our affection."
“骨肉之情却永不能割裂”
Lincoln said that in his first inaugural address as our nation's 16th president.
这是林肯就任美国第十六任总统时 所作的演讲
It's one of my favorites.
也是我的座右铭
So, if you'll please have your tickets ready...
把票准备好
we can begin the tour.
我们要开始参观了
Jackie, could you clear my schedule this evening?
贾姬，今天的所有行程取消
- I wanna have dinner with my son. - Yes, Mr. President.
- 我要和我儿子吃饭 - 是，总统先生
Excuse me, sir. Are you lost?
对不起，您迷路了吗？
Perimeter breach at visitor's checkpoint.
来宾登记处有人闯入
Multiple subjects.
不止一个人
- Mr. President, security breach. - Jackie, leave. Let's get him out to the car.
- 总统先生，有不速之客 - 贾姬，把他带上车
Exit's not clear. We don't know how many there are.
出口也不安全，对方人数不明
Post five. Secure.
这边很安全
- There's something in the corridor. - To the shelter.
- 走廊有人 - 带他去避难室
Negative! Not clear!
那里也不安全
- It's outside the oval office. - Lock this place down!
- 在椭圆办公室外面 - 封锁整个区域
- Don't shoot! - There!
- 别开枪！- 这边
My God.
老天
(保障变种人自由)
(亚卡利湖工业区)
Neanderthals. We once believed that they were wiped out...
我们的研究一度认为 尼安德特人
by years of conflict with a much more advanced branch of humanity...
在与更为进化的克罗马农人产生竞争时
called Cro-Magnon man.
就已经绝种
But recent research into our own DNA...
但是最近的对我们自身的DNA研究表明
suggests that these two species may have interbred...
这两大人种可能发生了混血
evolving into modern humans.
并且最终进化成了现代人类
- In otherwords, into what? - Us.
- 换句话说，进化成了 - 我们
Us. Right.
我们 没错
Artie, not here.
阿蒂 现在不行
Come on. Pay attention.
来，思想集中
Makes me insane when she does this.
..有时候她这样子真是令人发疯...
What are you looking at, you sick
你在找什么？
- I have cancer. -  To the shelter!
- 我得了癌症 - 快进避难室
They're gonna kill
他们想要杀了他
Jean? You okay?  Yeah.
琴？ 你没事吧？
Yeah, I'm fine.
没事
It's just, uh, just a headache.
就是有点头痛
It's notjust a headache, is it?
不止是头痛吧？
Listen, I... I wasn't really sure how to say this...
我说不清楚
- but ever since Liberty Island, you've been - Scott.
- 但是自从自由岛回来 - 斯科特
You've been different.
你就一直不太正常
My telepathy's been off lately.
我的心灵感应最近不太灵
- I can't seem to focus，I can hear everything. - It's not just your telepathy.
- 我没法集中精神，一片嘈杂  - 琴，问题不止是你的心灵感应
A month ago, you had to concentrate just to levitate a book or a chair across the room.
一个月前想让本书飘起来都要全神贯注
Now, when you have a nightmare, the entire bedroom shakes.
但是你现在做恶梦时 整个房间都会震动
My dreams are getting worse.
我的梦越来越可怕了
Scott.
斯科特
I keep feeling something terrible is about to happen.
我总是觉得有什么可怕的事情要发生
I would never let anything happen to you.
我不会让你发生意外的
Hey. Have you guys seen Bobby and Rogue?
你看到鲍比和小淘气吗？
Something's happening in the food court.
美食街有状况
- My brother asked you a simple question. - Why are you being such a dick?
- 问题很琴单 - 你凭什么耍屌？
Yeah, why are you being such a dick?
你为什么那么喜欢耍屌？
Because I can.
我有，我可以
Can I have a light?
借个火行吗？
- Sorry. I can't help you out, pal. - John, knock it off.
- 抱歉，伙计 - 琴，不要闹
Why don't you stop showing off?
你怎么不继续拽了？
- For her? - I can't help it if your girlfriend's getting excited.
- 为了她？ - 你马子爱看我也没办法
-  I don't think she's getting excited. - Trying to have a good time.
- 她不爱看 - 我们正想乐一乐
I think you're the only one having a good time.
你一个人乐去吧
That's real cute, man. What are you gonna do?
老兄，你可真逗 你想怎么样？
Suddenly, you're not so tough.
你怎么凶不起来了？
Bobby, what did you do?
鲍比，你在干吗呢？
- I didn't do this. - No.
- 不是我干的 - 对
I did.
是我干的
And the next time you feel like showing off, don't.
以后别再炫耀了
Breaking news. We're coming to you live from Washington...
爆炸新闻 华盛顿现场报道
where there's been an attack in the Oval Office of the White House.
白宫椭圆办公室遭到袭击
Details are still coming in, but we have been informed...
具体情况还在跟进当中 目前可以确定的是
that the president and vice-president were not harmed.
总统和副总统均安然无恙
Sources say the attack involved one or more mutants.
消息来源指出这可能是 一名甚至多名变种人所为...
I think it's time to leave, Professor.
我想我们该走了，教授
- Authorities have closed off - I think you're right.
- 当局已经… - 没错
(X教授 优秀青少年学校)
My opinion? Magneto's behind this.
以我看来，万磁王是幕后策划者
No. I don't think so, Scott.
我不觉得， 斯科特
While Eric is capable of organizing something like this from prison...
虽然艾瑞克可能像这样从监狱中 操纵这些事
for him it would be irrational.
但是这样做毫无意义
It would only hurt his goal of mutant prosperity.
并且只会妨碍他想让变种人兴旺的目标
- You mean superiority. - You're right.
- 你是说优等理论 - 没错
- If Eric had his way  - Of course, you know how the government will respond.
- 如果艾瑞克继续坚持的话 - 而且，政府会很自然的
They'll reintroduce the Registration Act.
再次提出变种人注册议案
Or worse. The president could declare a state ofemergency.
或许更糟 总统可以宣布戒严
Place every mutant in the country under arrest.
然后把所有的变种人扔到牢里去
Do you think the assassin was working alone?
你觉得行刺总统是单独行动的？
Well, we'll only know that if we find him before the authorities do.
找到他就知道了
I've been trying to track him using Cerebro...
他的行动太飘忽不定了
but his movements are inexplicably erratic.
我用脑波强化机很难追踪到他
When I have more exact coordinates...
等我确切锁定目标以后
Storm, Jean, I'll need you to take the jet and try and pick him up.
风暴女，琴 你们去把他弄回来
It was close, wasn't it?
真是好险啊
Closer than anyone's admitted.
超乎想象的险
- What do you need, William? - Just your authorization...
- 你想要什么， 威廉？ - 要你授权我
for a special operation.
进行一项特别行动
Uh, no, thank you, Mr. President.
不，谢谢，总统先生
And somehow I thought you were here to talk about school reform.
我以为你是来跟我谈学校改革计划的
Funny you should say that, Mr. President.
总统先生，您真幽默
- Senator.- Mr. President.
- 参议员 - 总统先生
- Thank you for having me. - Senator Kelly, this is Colonel William Stryker.
- 感谢您的邀请 - 克雷参议员, 这位是威廉-史崔克上校.
- How do you do? - His department has been dealing with the mutant phenomenon...
- 你好 - 我上任以来
since before my time.
变种人一直由他的部门负责
As I recall, you were a staunch supporter of the Registration Act, Senator.
你是变种人注册法案的忠实拥护者
It seems your ideas on the mutant problem have changed recently.
不过看来你对变种人的态度有所改变
For the best, I hope.
这是为大局着想，总统先生
So, what are you proposing, Mr. Stryker?
那么你有什么建议，史崔克先生?
Uh, may I, Mr. President?
可以坐下吗，总统先生？
We've managed to gather evidence of a mutant training facility...
我们收集到了一些证据 显示纽约北郊的一个训练机构
in the Salem region of upstate New York.
专门训练变种人
Where did you get this information?
你的消息来源可靠吗？
Interrogation of one of the mutant terrorists...
审问一名自由岛事件的
from the Liberty Island incident.
恐怖分子
Eric? Eric Lehnsherr?
艾瑞克-兰瑟？
- You have access to him? - Magneto. Yes.
- 你跟他谈过了？ - 没错，万磁王
We developed the technology that built his plastic prison.
我们为他设计了最新的塑料监狱
- This facility is a school. - Sure it is.
- 那个训练机构是个学校 - 毫无疑问
- What the hell is that? - A jet.
- 这是什么鬼东西？ - 喷射器
- What kind of jet? - We don't know...
- 什么喷射器？ - 不知道
but it comes up out of the basketball court.
但是从篮球场就可以起飞
If we'd been allowed to do our jobs, Mr. President, before this incident-
如果我们事发前可以采取行动...
All right. Listen.
好，听着
William, you enter, you detain, you question...
威廉，你有权搜查、拘留、审讯
but the last thing we need to see...
不过不要让我在六点新闻看到
is the body of a mutant kid on the 6:00 news.
变种人小孩被滥杀的尸体
- Mr. Stryker. - Senator Kelly.
- 史崔克先生? - 克雷参议员
This is Yuriko, my personal assistant.
这位是百合子， 我的私人助理
- Quite a handshake. - What can I do foryou?
- 好强的手劲 - 有什么可以效劳的吗？
Uh, Eric Lehnsherr's prison. I'd like to arrange a visit if possible.
我想要拜访一下 监狱里的艾瑞克-兰瑟
It isn't a petting zoo, Senator.
那可不是宠物乐园，参议员先生
In this conflict, he is the enemy.
在这场冲突中，他是主角
You're just a spectator. So why don't you sit this one out, all right?
你只是观众，不要趟这个浑水
Conflict? Mr. Stryker, do you really want to turn this into some kind of war?
冲突？ 史崔克先生 你真的想要挑起战争吗？
I was piloting black-ops missions in thejungles of North Vietnam...
你还在妈妈怀里吃奶的时候
while you were sucking on your mama's tit at Woodstock, Kelly.
我已经在越南指挥特种行动了
Don't lecture me about war.
别跟我提战争
This already is a war.
战争早就已经开始了
- You're dead. - You're so dead.  You're dead.
- 你死定了 - 你才死定了
I...I don't wanna hurt you.
我不想伤害你
I'm not afraid.
我没有恶意
Logan! It's Logan.
罗根
You miss me, kid?
想我吗？
Not really. Mm. How you doing?
不太想 你还好吗？
I'm okay. How are you? Who's this?
挺好，你呢？ 这是谁？
- Oh, this is Bobby. He's my  - I'm her boyfriend.
- 这是 鲍比. 他是我的… - 我是她男朋友
Call me Iceman.
叫我低温侠
Right. Boyfriend?
很好 男朋友？
So how do you guys-
你们两个可以？
Well, we're still working on that.
我们正在想办法
Look who's come back. Just in time.
看谁回来了，真巧
- For what? - We need a baby-sitter.
- 巧什么？ - 我们正需要一个保姆
- Baby-sitter? - Nice to see you again, Logan.
- 保姆？ - 很高兴再次见到你，罗根
- Hi, Logan. - Hi, Jean.
- 嗨, 罗根 - 嗨, 琴
Uh, I should go and get the jet ready.
我得去把喷射器准备好
Yeah, well, it was good to meet you.
很高兴认识你
- Come on. - Let's go. Bye, Logan.
- 来吧，我们走 - 再见，罗根
-  I'll see you later. - Okay.
- 回头见 - 好
Storm and I are heading to Boston.
暴风女和我打算去波士顿
We won't be gone long.
我们不会离开很久
The professor wants us to track down a mutant who attacked the president.
教授想要我们 找到那个袭击总统的人
So it was a mutant?
那么果然是变种人干的了
You'll be here when we get back...
在这里等我们回来
unless you plan on running off again.
除非你又像上次一样偷溜
Well, I can probably think of a few reasons to stick around.
我会尽量想办法留在这里
Find what you were looking for, Logan?
找到你要的东西了吗，罗根？
More or less.
多少找到一点
I'll see you boys later.
回头见
- Be safe, okay? - You too.
- 小心点 - 你也是
- Bye. - See ya.
- 再见了 - 再见
Aren't you gonna welcome me home?
我回家你不欢迎吗？
Your bike needs gas.
你的车该加油了
Then fill her up.
那就去加啊
Mr. Laurio.
罗里奥先生
How long can we keep this up?
这种状态还要持续多久？
How long is your sentence?
你的刑期有多长？
Forever. Not necessarily forever, Mr. Lehnsherr.
永远 不一定非得要永远的，兰瑟先生
Just until I've got all that I need.
只要你能告诉我我想知道的
Mr. Stryker. How kind of you to visit.
史崔克先生 你能来真是太好了
Have you come back to make sure the tax-payers' dollars are keeping me comfortable?
是来看看你花了纳税人的钱 把我服侍得够不够舒服吧？
Done. You can go.
行了，你可以走了
Now...
现在
Mr. Lehnsherr...
兰瑟先生
I'd like to have one final talk...
我想最后再聊一下
about the house that Xavier built...
关于X教授的训练基地
and the machine called Cerebro.
和那个所谓的脑波强化机
Logan, my tolerance foryour smoking in the mansion notwithstanding...
虽然我可以忍受你在室内抽烟
continue smoking that in here and you'll spend the rest of your days...
但是如果你在这里继续抽 你的智力一辈子都会
under the beliefthat you're a six-year-old girl.
像个六岁的小女孩
- You'd do that? - I'd have Jean braid your hair.
- 你做得到吗？ - 我会让琴帮你梳辫子
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
You want me to leave?
你想让我出去？
No. Just don't move.
别，就在这里吧
These lights represent every living person on the planet.
这些光线代表地球上的每个人
White lights are humans.
白色的代表普通人类
And these are the mutants.
这种红色的则是变种人
Through Cerebro, I'm connected to them.
我能通过脑波强化机跟他们连接
And they to me.
他们也跟我连接
You see, Logan...
看到吗，罗根
We're not as alone as you think.
你说的没错 我们并不孤独
I found the base at Alkali Lake.
我找到了亚卡利湖的基地
There was nothing there.
那里什么也没有
The broken line represents the path ofthe mutant who attacked the president.
这条虚线显示出 袭击总统的变种人的行动路线
I've been finding it difficult to get a lock on him.
我觉得很难锁定到他
Well, can't you just concentrate harder?
你不能更集中注意力和他连接吗？
If I wanted to kill him, yes.
除非我想杀了他
There.
在那儿
Looks like he's finally stopped running.
看上去他终于停下来了
[祷告]
I need you to read my mind again.
请你再扫描一次我的思想
Logan...
罗根…
I'm afraid the results will be the same as before.
和上次的结果一样
- We had a deal. - The mind is not a box that can be simply unlocked and opened.
- 我们约好了的 - 心灵不是个随便就能打开的箱子
- It's a beehive with a million different compartments. - Spare me the lecture.
- 它就像是成百万的… - 收起你的演讲吧
I have no doubt that your amnesia, your adamantium skeleton, the claws...
我非常确定，你的失忆症 你的钢筋铁骨，你的尖牙利爪之间
are all somehow connected.
有着复杂的联系
But, Logan...
但是 罗根…
sometimes the mind needs to discover things for itself.
有些事得要让心灵自己去发现
I promise you we'll talk again when I return.
我答应，等我回来我会再跟你谈谈
Oh. If you will be kind enough to watch over the children tonight...
麻烦你照看我的孩子们
Scott and I are going to visit an old friend.
斯科特和我今天要去拜访一下老朋友
I'm sending coordinates of where the mutant seems to have settled for now.
我会把那个变种人的坐标传过去
Soon as you find him, bring him back to the mansion.
你们找到他后 尽快把他带回来
Let's hope he cooperates.
但愿他能够合作
Yes. For his sake. Good luck.
是啊，为了他自己的性命，保重
Stryker, William.
史崔克-威廉
(准许进入)
(兰瑟 艾瑞克)
(打印)
(脑波强化机)
(强化机1)
(强化机2)
(行动基地)
(地点：机密)
(打印)
What are you doing in here?
你在这里干什么
Garbage.
扫垃圾
These are the coordinates.
坐标位置就在这里
滚出去
我是恶魔的使者
我是恶魔的
后代
He's a teleporter.
他会瞬间移动
Must be why the professor had trouble locking onto him.
难怪教授不能锁定他
We're not here to hurt you!
我们不是来伤害你的
We just wanna talk!
只是想跟你谈谈
滚出去 我是恶魔的使者 我是恶魔的…
- Are you bored yet? - Oh, yeah.
- 听腻了吧？ - 是啊
Sure you don't wanna come down?
你打算下来了吗？
- You have him? - He's not going anywhere.
- 抓住他了？ - 他跑不掉了
Are you?
够了吗？
Please don't kill me. I didn't mean to harm anyone.
不要杀我 我不想杀害任何人
Now why would people have gotten that impression?
为什么别人都不是这么想？
- What's your name? - Wagner. Kurt Wagner.
- 你的名字是？ - 瓦格纳，克特-瓦格纳
(柏林马戏团)
There was so much shooting...
那里满是枪声
such fear...
我很怕…
and then there was only pain.
很痛苦…
I could see it all happening...
我眼看着它发生
but I couldn't stop myself.
但却没法阻止
It was like a bad dream.
简直像个恶梦
Perhaps He is testing me.
也许他在考验我
And before you were in the White House...
在你进白宫之前的事情
what do you remember?
你还记得多少？
Nothing. I was here.
什么也没有 我就是在那里
Jean.
琴
I'd rather get him back to the professor.
我想带他去见教授
The professor?
教授？
Did you do these yourself?
是你自己干的？
Yes.
是的
And what about this?
这是什么意思？
I need you to read my mind again.
请你再读一次我的思想
I'm afraid the results will be the same as before.
结果肯定还是一样
- He'll be indestructible. - His entire skeleton-
- 你会拥有金刚不坏之身 - 没有记忆了
Adamantium.  Sometimes the mind needs to discover things for itself.
有些事情要靠心灵自己去发现
Wolverine.
狼人
No memory. He'll have no memory.
没有记忆，你将会失去记忆
Can't sleep?
睡不着？
- How can you tell? - Cause you're awake.
- 你怎么知道？ - 因为你醒着
Right. How about you?
没错，你呢？
I don't sleep.
我从来不睡
Doesn't anybody sleep around here?
这里的人都不用睡觉？
Apparently not.
很明显啊
- Got any beer? - This is a school.
- 有啤酒吗？ - 这里是学校
- So that's a "no"? - Yeah, that's a "no".
- 所以答案是没有？ - 没错
Got anything other than chocolate milk?
除了巧克力和牛奶就没有别的了？
There should be some soda in that small cupboard.
柜子里有苏打水
- Thanks. - No problem.
- 谢谢 - 不用了
I'll take him from here.
我要把他弄出来
It's all right, Scott.
没问题，斯科特
- Nice shades. - Thanks.
- 墨镜很酷嘛 - 谢谢夸奖
Charles Xavier. Have you come to rescue me?
查尔斯-泽维尔 你是来救我的吗？
Sorry, Eric. Not today.
对不起，艾瑞克，今天不行
To what do I owe the pleasure?
俗话说无事不登三宝殿
The assassination attempt on the president-
袭击总统的事
- What do you know about it?- Nothing.
- 你知道多少？ - 除了报纸上的新闻
Only what I read in the papers.
一无所知
You really shouldn't have to ask, Charles.
你完全不必问我
What's happened to you?
你怎么回事？
I've had frequent visits from William Stryker.
威廉-史崔克 经常来拜访我
You remember him, don't you?
你还记得这家伙吧？
William Stryker.
威廉-史崔克
His son, Jason, was once a student of yours, wasn't he?
他儿子詹森，曾经是你的学生 没错吧？
Yes. Years ago.
是啊，很多年以前的事了
Unfortunately, I wasn't able to help him...
不幸的是，我帮不了他
at least not in the way that his father wanted.
至少不像他父亲希望的那样帮他
And now you think that taking in the Wolverine...
现在你接纳狼人
will make up for your failure with Strykef's son.
就能弥补当年他儿子的遗憾？
- How long you been here? - Couple years.
- 你来这里多久了？ - 好几年了
And your parents just sent you off to mutant school?
是你父母要送你进变种人学校的？
Actually, my parents think this is a prep school.
实际上他们以为这里是大学预科班
Oh, I see.
我明白了
- I suppose lots of prep schools have their own dorms, campuses - Jets.
- 很多预科班都有独立的宿舍和校园 - 喷射器
- So you and Rogue, huh? - Yeah.
- 你和罗杰… - 是呀
It's not what you think. I'd like it to be, but it'sjust-
我希望是这样 但总是事与愿违…
It's just that it's not easy...
想接近一个人
when you wanna be closer to someone...
却办不到是件
but you can't.
很痛苦的事
You know, I've seen how you look at Dr. Grey.
我注意到你看葛雷博士的眼神
- Excuse me? - Nothing.
- 怎么？ - 没什么
You haven't told him about his past, have you?
你没有告诉他你的过去吧？
I've put him on the path.
我绕过了没提
Logan's mind is still fragile.
罗根的精神还是很脆弱
Is it?
不是吗？
Or are you afraid of losing one of your precious X-Men...
你很怕失去一个挚爱的X战警吧？
old friend?
老朋友
Eric, what have you done?
艾瑞克，你干了什么？
I'm sorry, Charles.
对不起，查尔斯
I couldn't help it.
我忍不住
What have you told Stryker?
你跟史崔克说了什么？
Everything.
一切都说了
The war has begun.
战鼓已经擂响
Scott! You should've killed me when you had the chance!
斯科特! 你有机会的时候早该杀了我的
But now and then...
但是现在
every mother needs to get away.
妈妈经常会离开孩子们
Without her, the babies are helpless.
没有了妈妈，孩子们岌岌可危…
Hi.
嗨
- What is it? - Shh, shh.
- 这是什么？ - 嘘 嘘
You picked the wrong house, bub.
你选错了房子
You all right?
你没事吧？
Stay here.
在这儿别动
Come on! Run!
快点，快跑
Move, move, move!
行动！行动！
- This way. - Let's go. Come on!
- 走这边 - 我们走
Run! John! Hey. Where's Rogue?
约翰！罗杰呢？
- I don't know. - I gotta find her.
- 我不知道 - 我去找她
- Come on! - Here. Take her.
- 打开 - 这里，帮一把
Go on. Get in. Let's go. Let's go.
继续，进去，我们走
Hey. Take him. He's stunned.
帮他一把，他昏过去了
- I can help you. - Help them.
- 我来帮你 - 帮他们吧
- Rogue! - Bobby!
- 罗杰！ - 鲍比！
This way.
这边
Come on. Everybody, follow me up here.
跟我来，大伙加油
Move! Move! Go! Go!
快一点
Come on.
加油
Let's go.
我们走
Come on. This way.
来，这边
This is it.
就是这里
Logan!
罗根
You wanna shoot me? Shoot me!
想杀了我吗？发射啊
Don't shoot him!
别射他
Not yet.
时机未到
Wolverine?
狼人？
Well, I must admit, this is certainly the last place...
我承认没想到
I'd expect to find you.
会在这里碰上你
How long has it been? Fifteen years?
我们有多久没见了，15年？
You haven't changed one bit.
你一点都没变
Me, on the other hand-
另一方面，我…
Nature.
自然规律
Wait! Wait! You guys, we gotta do something. They're gonna kill him.
等一下，我们得采取行动 他们会杀了他
- He can handle himself. Let's go. - Bobby!
- 他能保护好自己，我们走 - 鲍比.
Please.
拜托…
I didn't realize Xavier was taking in animals...
我没想到泽维尔还会训练动物
even animals as unique as you.
甚至你这种德行的动物
Who are you?
你是谁？
Don't you remember?
你忘了吗？
No! No!
不！
Logan, come on. Let's go.
罗根，来，我们走
- Logan. Go! - I'll be fine.
- 罗根 - 走，我没事的
But we won't.
不行
Go. Keep going.
走，别停下
- All right. Get in. Get in! - I'm driving.
- 好，进去 - 我来驾驶
Hey. Maybe next time.
下次吧
This is Cyclops's car.
这是独眼龙的车
Oh, yeah?
真的？
What the hell was that back there?
什么鬼地方，这么黑？
Stryker. His name is Stryker.
史崔克.他名叫史崔克.
Who is he?
他是谁？
I can't remember.
我不记得了
Here. This is yours.
拿去 这是你的
I don't like uncomfortable silences.
我讨厌这么安静，不自在
What are you doing?
你在干吗？
I don't think that's the CD player.
我觉得这个不是随身听
Sit back.
坐好
- Where we going? - Storm and Jean are in Boston. We'll head that way.
- 我们去哪里？ - 暴风女和琴在波士顿 去找他们
- My parents live in Boston. - Good.
- 我的父母都住在波士顿 - 好极了
Sergeant?
长官？
Most of the mutants escaped through a series oftunnels that weren't in our schematics.
很多变种人从地道逃跑了
We have several in custody.
我们在监管室抓到几个
- How many? - Six, sir.
- 几个？ - 六个，长官
Welcome, Professor.
欢迎，教授
Take what we need, gentlemen.
把我们需要的都带走，先生们
Look, I just think all this anti-mutant protesting...
这个提案显示
underscores the genuine growing concern among most Americans.
当前国民普遍关心的问题
- I think mutant registration... - But why stop there?
- 变种人注册 - 注册还不够
Maybe it would be easier to round up mutants by the truckload.
干脆全部装卡车运进集中营
- Or maybe you'd like all-out war, Mr. Shaw. - Oh, please.
- 或者你更喜欢全面的战争？ - 拜托…
Turn that shit off, Lou.
别看这些狗屎，罗
Lot on your mind?
你有心事？
Mr. Laurio?
罗里奥先生？
I'm Grace.
我是葛雷斯
You want another beer?
还要啤酒吗？
Of course you do.
当然
- You're really aggressive. - Yes, I am.
- 你很主动 - 当然了
Oh, I...I've never hooked up with a girl like you before.
我还从来没你这样的姑娘吸引住
I know.
看得出来
It's, uh, kinda dirty in here, don't you think?
这里真够脏的
That's the idea. Velcro.
脏不是挺好的 维克牢？
- Nice. - Bottom's up.
- 很不错 - 干杯！
I certainly hope so.
我很希望如此
Bottom's up.
干杯
- William. - Please, Xavier, don't get up.
- 威廉… - 泽维尔，不必站起来
I call it the neural inhibitor.
这东西叫神经抑制器
It keeps you outta here.
让你无法发挥能力
What have you done with Scott?
你对斯科特干了什么?
Don't worry. I'm just giving him a little reeducation.
别担心 只是给教他一点新知识
Of course, you know all about that, don't you?
你对此再清楚不过，不是吗？
William, you wanted me to cure your son.
你要我治好你儿子
- But mutation is not a disease. - You're lying!
- 但是变种并不是一种疾病 - 你胡说
You were more frightened of him than I was.
你比我还怕他
You know, just one year after Jason returned from your school...
詹森从你的学校回来后一年
my wife
我妻子…
You see he resented us.
你知道，他恨我们
He blamed us for his condition.
他怨我们造成了他现在的模样
So he would toy with our minds...
于是就以折磨我们的思想为乐
projecting visions and scenarios into our brains.
让我们的脑中充满幻想
Well, my wife, in the end-
最后，我妻子她…
She took a power drill to her left temple...
为了赶走那些恐怖的幻想
in an attempt to bore the images out.
用电钻钻进了太阳穴
My boy, the great illusionist.
我的孩子… 是个幻想大师
For someone who hates mutants...
即使像你这么痛恨变种人
you certainly keep some strange company.
你还是和他们成为同伴
Oh, they serve their purpose...
只要控制有方
as long as they can be controlled.
他们还是很能干的
You arranged the attack on the president.
袭击总统的事件是你策划的？
You didn't even have to read my mind.
你不用读我的心思就能知道
You know, I've been working with mutants as long as you have, Xavier...
我和变种人合作的时间 一点也不比你短
but the most frustrating thing I've learned...
不过最令人发愁的是
is that nobody really knows how many even exist...
你永远不知道世界上有多少变种人
or how to find them...
以及怎么找出他们
except you.
除了你
Unfortunately, this little potion won't work on you, will it?
可惜，这些药对你来说有点太少了
You're much too powerful for that.
你的力量强大得多
Instead, we'll go right to the source.
所以我们只好另辟蹊径
Allow me to introduce mutant 143.
请允许我向您介绍 变种人143号
The fluid secreted by his brain acts as a mind-controlling agent.
脑部分泌的液体可控制他人的思想
But that's only where it begins.
不过目前还处于试验阶段
Jason.
詹森？
Oh, my God, William. This is your son.
天那，威廉，这是你的儿子
- What have you done to him? - No, Charles!
- 你对他干了什么？ - 不，查尔斯
My son is dead...
我儿子已经死了
just like the rest of you.
就像你们一样
Mom? Dad? Ronny?
妈妈？爸爸？罗尼？
Is anybody home?
有谁在家吗？
I'll try and find us some clothes.
我来找件衣服给你
Don't burn anything.
别玩火
Hey. I found some of my mom's old clothes.
我找到几件我妈的旧衣服
I think they're from before I was born.
好像是我出生以前的衣服
Groovy.
很一般
Hello.
你好
Come on, Jean. Where are you?
琴，你在哪里？
These are my grandmother's.
这是我祖母的
Thanks.
谢谢
You won't hurt me.
你不会伤害我
I'm...I'm sorry.
对不起
It's okay.
不要紧
Hey, Ronny. Next time you-
罗尼，下次换你
Who the hell are you?
你是谁？
Uh...Bobby.
鲍比
Honey, aren't you supposed to be at school?
你应该在学校里吧？
-  Bobby, who is this guy? - Uh, this is Professor Logan.
- 鲍比，这家伙是谁？ - 这是罗根教授
There's something I need to tell you.
我有点事要告诉你
(检测)
(扫描完成)
You're clear.
通过
Have a nice sleep, Lehnsherr?
睡得好吗，兰瑟？
There's something different about you, Mr. Laurio.
你有点不太正常
Yeah. I was having a good day.
是啊，我很开心
No. No, it's not that.
不是这个意思
- Sit down. - No.
- 坐下 - 不
Sit your ass down.
给我他妈的坐下
What could it be?
那会怎么样？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Ahh. There it is.
原来如此
Too much iron in your blood.
血液中铁含量过高
Mr. Laurio, never trust a beautiful woman...
罗里奥先生, 永远不要相信美女
especially one who's interested in you.
尤其是当她对你有兴趣的时候
when did you first know you were a-
你是什么时候知道自己…
A...A mutant?
是个变种人的？
Would you cut that out?
能不提这些吗？
You have to understand,
你必须理解
We thought Bobby was going to a school for the gifted.
我们以为鲍比念的是天才学校
- Bobby is gifted. - We know that. We just didn't realize he was-
- 鲍比的确是个天才 - 我们知道，只是还不太明白…
We still love you, Bobby. It's just this mutant problem is a little-
我们一直都爱你， 鲍比. 只是变种人的问题有点…
- What mutant problem? - Complicated.
- 什么变种人的问题？ - …很复杂
What exactly are you a professor of, Mr. Logan?
你究竟是研究什么的教授？
Art.
艺术
Well, you should see what Bobby can do.
你得看看 鲍比 的能力
Bobby.
鲍比
I can do a lot more than that.
我的能力决不止于此
Oh. Ronny!
罗尼
- This is all my fault. - Actually...
- 都是我的错 - 实际上…
they discovered that males are the ones who carry the mutant gene and pass it on...
应该是他的错
so it's his fault.
因为这基因来自男性亲代
911. Please state your emergency.
这里是911. 请说明你的情况
I need the police. There are people in our house.
我们需要警察，有人闯进我家
They won't let us leave.  Authorities refused to comment...
胁持我的家人
but it's believed that a manhunt for several fugitives from the facility...
追捕行动
is now underway.
正在展开
Nobody's responding. I can't get a signal.
没有回应，失去信号
Why don't you take a break? I'll keep trying.
你休息一下吧，我来继续
[祷告]
So, what are they?
这些是什么？
They are angelic symbols...
他们是大天使加百利
passed on to mankind by the Archangel Gabriel.
带到人间的天使的图腾
They're beautiful. How many do you have?
非常美 你有几种？
One for every sin...
每种罪恶都有相对应的一种
so quite a few.
真不少
You and Miss Grey are schoolteachers?
你和葛雷小姐是老师吗？
Yes. At a school for people like us... where we can be safe.
是啊，在我们这种人的学校 保护我们的安全
Safe from what?
保护谁的安全？
Everyone else.
其他所有人
You know, outside ofthe circus, most people were afraid of me.
马戏团以外的人都很怕我
But I didn't hate them. I pitied them.
不过我不恨他们，我只怜悯他们
Do you know why?
知道为什么吗？
Because most people will never know anything...
绝大多数人对他们肉眼
beyond what they see with their own two eyes.
看不到的世界一无所知
Well, I gave up on pity a long time ago.
我很早就开始不再同情他们了
Someone so beautiful should not be so angry.
如此美丽的人不该这样愤怒的
Sometimes anger...
有时候愤怒
can help you survive.
也能救命呢
So can faith.
信仰也可以救命
Storm, I found an active com device.
暴风女，我找到联络设备了
Where?
在哪儿？
Oh, it's for me.
上帝，这是给我的
Bobby...
鲍比
have you tried not being a mutant?
你有没有试过把自己当作正常人？
No one's left, Jean. Soldiers came.
一个不剩，琴，有军队来过了
- What about the children? - Some of them escaped. I'm not sure about the rest.
- 孩子们呢？ - 我看到一部分人逃脱，其他人下落不明
We haven't been able to reach the professor or Scott either.
教授和斯科特都联络不上
- Where are you, Logan? - Boston, with Bobby Drake's family.
- 你在哪里？ - 波士顿，和 鲍比-达瑞克一家在一起
- Okay. We're on ourway. - And Storm? Make it fast.
- 很好，我们上路了 - 暴风女，快一点
- We have to go now.- Why?
- 我们要出发了 - 怎么了？
Now! Logan, what's wrong?
罗根，什么问题？
Drop the knives and put your hands in the air.
扔掉刀子，举起手来
-  What's going on here? - Ronny.
- 发生了什么事？ - 罗尼
I said drop the knives.
我说把刀子扔掉
- Open the door! - Break it.
- 开门 - 撞开它
Turn around.
转过去
- Up against the wall. - Okay!
- 对着墙站好 - 好的
- This is just a misunderstanding. - Put the knives down.
- 这都是误会 - 放下刀子
I can't.
我办不到
Look.
看着
All right, the rest of you, on the ground now.
其他人，都给我趴下
Look, kid, I said on the ground.
孩子，我说趴下
We don't want to hurt you, kid.
我们不想伤害你，孩子
You know all those dangerous mutants you hear about on the news?
你听过新闻，知道变种人很危险吧？
I'm the worst one.
我是最危险的那个
Look out!
当心！
- Who the hell is this? - Kurt Wagner.
- 这是谁？ - 克特-瓦格纳
But in the Munich circus, I was known as "the Incredible Nightcrawler".
马戏团里的称号是“不可思议的蓝魔鬼”
- Aw, save it. Storm? - We're outta here.
- 省点力气吧，暴风女 - 我们走
Jason, stop it!
詹森，停下
It's all right.
没事了
- You can come out. - Have they gone?
- 你可以出来了 - 他们都走了吗？
Yes.
是的
- Where are all the other students? - I don't know.
- 其他的学生都去哪了？ - 不知道
Well, then, we'll have to find them, won't we?
那我们要找到他们才行
We'll use Cerebro.
我们用脑波强化器来找
Come on.
来吧
How far are we?
还有多远？
We're actually coming up on the mansion now.
我们就快到学校上空了
I've got two signals approaching.
信号显示有两架飞机向我们飞来
Coming in fast.
速度很快
Unidentified aircraft, you are ordered to descend to 20,000 feet.
不明身份飞机, 命令你立即下降到2万英尺
Return with our escort to Hanscom Air Force base. You have 10 seconds to comply.
由我们护送返回汗斯卡姆空军基地 限你10秒钟之内照办
- Wow. Somebody's angry. - I wonder why.
- 哇哦,脾气不小 - 为什么呢
We are coming up alongside you to escort you to Hanscom Air Force base.
我们将接近你们侧方, 护送你们前往汗斯卡姆空军基地
Lower your altitude now.
请立即降低高度
Repeat, loweryour altitude to 20,000 feet. This is your last warning.
重复：下降到2万英尺 这是最后一次警告
They're falling back.
他们撤后了
They're marking us.
他们在锁定我们
- What? - They're gonna fire. Hang on!
- 什么？ - 要开火了，坐稳
I gotta shake 'em.
我要甩掉他们
- Please don't do that again. - I agree.
- 请别再那么干了 - 我同意
Don't we have any weapons in this heap?
这破玩意儿上就没武器么？
Warning, warning, warning.
警报 警报 警报
Warning, warning, warning, warning, warning.
警报 警报 警报 警报 警报
Warning, warning, warning, warning, warning, warning.
警报 警报 警报 警报 警报 警报
Warning, warning, warning
警报 警报 警报
- Everybody okay back there? - No.
- 大家都还好吗？ - 不怎么样
Oh, my God. There's two of'em.
天啊，有两枚导弹
There's one more.
还有一枚
Jean
琴？
Oh, God!
哦，天哪
Rogue!
罗杰
No!
不
- Jean? - It's not me.
- 琴？ - 不是我干的
When will these people learn how to fly?
这些家伙什么时候才能学会开飞机？
- Thank you. - Bitte sch?n.
- 谢谢你 - 没什么
- Can you hear what they're saying? - I could take a closer look.
- 你能听到他们说话吗？ - 我可以再凑近瞧瞧
His name is Colonel William Stryker...
他是威廉 史崔克上校
and he invaded your mansion for one purpose:
他袭击学校的目的只有一个
He wanted Cerebro.
就是得到脑波强化器
Or enough of it to build one of his own.
或者收集足够的部件自己再造一个
But that doesn't make any sense. Stryker would need the professor to operate it.
那说不通啊 史崔克一定要教授才能操作啊
Which I think is the only reason my old friend is still alive.
我认为这正是我的老朋友还活着的唯一原因
Oh, my God.
哦，天啊！
Now, what are you all so afraid of?
你们都在害怕什么？
While Cerebro is working, Charles' mind is connected...
脑波强化器工作时 查尔斯的大脑
to every living person on the planet.
会与地球上每个人相连
If he were forced to concentrate hard enough on a particular group...
如果他被迫将足够强的意识 集中在某个特定人群上
let's say, mutants, for example...
比如：变种人
- he could kill us all. - Wait a minute.
- 他能把我们都杀死 - 等等，首先告诉我
How would Stryker even know where to find Cerebro in the first place?
史崔克怎么会知道脑波强化器在哪？
Because I told him.
我告诉他的
I helped Charles build it, remember?
还记得么？是我帮着查尔斯制造的
Mr. Stryker has powerful methods of persuasion.
史崔克先生的说服能力很强
Even against a mutant as strong as Charles.
即使像查尔斯那样强大的变种人都无法抵抗
- So who's this Stryker anyway? - He's a military scientist.
- 那这个史崔克到底是什么人？ - 他是个军方科学家
He spent his whole life trying to solve the mutant problem.
他一生致力于解决变种人的问题
If you want a more intimate perspective, why don't you ask Wolverine?
如果你想知道的更详细一点, 为什么不去问问狼人
You don't remember, do you?
你不记得了吧,嗯？
William Stryker, the only other man I know who can manipulate adamantium.
除我之外 威廉 史崔克是唯一能处理合成细胞的人
The metal on your bones. It carries his signature.
你骨骼里的金属就是他的杰作
- But the professor - The professor trusted...
- 但是教授 - 他相信
you were smart enough to discover this on your own.
你会自己发现这件事的
He gives you more credit than I do.
他比我更加相信你
- Why do you need us? - Mystique has discovered plans of a base...
- 你为什么需要我们帮忙？ - 变色龙发现了史崔克建立基地的蓝图
that Stryker's been operating out of for decades.
那里已经运行几十年了
We know that's where he's building the second Cerebro...
我们知道他在那里造第二台脑波强化器
but we don't know where this base is...
但不知道基地的位置
and I believe one of you might.
我认为你们有人知道
- The professor already tried. - Once again, you think it's all about you.
- 教授已经试过了 - 你又认为你是主角
Oh... hello.
你好 不好意思
- I didn't mean to snoop. - Just try and relax.
- 我不是故意要偷听的 - 尽量放松
I'm sorry.
对不起
Strykef's at Alkali Lake.
史崔克在亚克利湖
That's where the professor sent me. There's nothing left.
教授就是让我去那里的 那里什么都没有
There's nothing left on the surface, Logan. The base is underground.
地面上是没什么，罗根 基地在地底下
You okay?
你还好么？
- Yeah. - You sure?
- 还好 - 真的？
- How we doing?-  Not good.
- 飞机怎么样？ - 不妙
It'll take four or five hours before I can get it off the ground.
看起来要花4,5个小时才能修好
That's not what I meant.
我不是问这个
- I'm just worried about Scott. - I'm worried about you.
- 我有点担心斯科特 - 我却担心你
That was some display of power up there.
刚才在天上你的表现令人惊讶
- Obviously, it wasn't enough.- Hey, hey. Come on. All right?
- 明显还不够 - 打起精神
I love him.
我爱他
Do you?
真的？
Girls flirt with the dangerous guy, Logan...
女孩们喜欢与危险的家伙调情，罗根
they don't take him home.
却不会带他回家
They marry the good guy.
她们会嫁给好男人
I could be the good guy.
我可以当好男人
Logan, the good guy sticks around.
罗根，好男人不会到处跑的
- Jean. - Please. Please.
- 琴  - 不要 不要
- Don't make me do this. - Do what?
- 不要逼我这样 - 怎样？
This.
这样
Excuse me.
打搅一下
They say you can imitate any body... even their voice.
他们说你能模仿任何人 连声音都能模仿
Even their voice.
连声音都能模仿
Then why not stay in disguise all the time?
那干吗不一直伪装呢？
You know, look like everyone else.
我是说… 让自己像其他人一样
Because we shouldn't have to.
因为没这个必要
Look
听着
No one's ever left a scar quite like you.
没有人能像你给我留下这样的疤痕
What do you want, an apology?
你想要什么？道歉？
You know what I want.
你知道我要什么
But what do you want?
但是你想要什么？
What do you really want?
你到底要什么？
I want you to get out.
我要你滚出去
Jesus.
上帝
- Why don't we get uniforms?- Yeah, where's ours?
- 我们怎么没有制服？ - 对啊，我们的呢？
They're on order. Should arrive in a few years.
已经订了 再过几年应该会来的
We love what you've done with your hair.
我喜欢你做的发型
Hey, hey. Come on. Let's go.
嘿，嘿！ 算了，我们走吧
So, they say you're the bad guy.
他们说你是坏蛋
Is that what they say?
他们这么说？
That's a dorky-looking helmet. What's it for?
这个甲虫似的头盔真丑 干什么用的？
This dorky-looking helmet is the only thing that's gonna protect me...
只有这个丑头盔才能保护
from the real bad guys.
我不受真正的坏蛋伤害
- What's your name? - John.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 约翰
What's your real name, John?
你的真名呢？约翰
Pyro.
火人
Quite a talent you have there, Pyro.
火人，你的本事相当棒
I can only manipulate the fire.
我只能舞火
I can't create it.
不能造火
You are a god among insects.
你是渺渺众生中的神
Never let anyone tell you different.
不要让人察觉你的非同凡响
Sir, the machine has been completed to all specifications.
长官，机器已经按预定完成
Good.
不错
If I may ask, sir, why are we keeping the children here?
我想问 我们干吗还要留着这些孩子？
I'm a scientist, Sergeant Lyman.
我是个科学家，莱曼中尉
When I build a machine, I wanna make sure that it's working.
我造的机器一定要能用
All right, this is a topographic map of the dam.
看，这是大坝的地形图
This is the spillway.
这是泄洪道
You see these density changes in the terrain?
看到这些疏密相间的图像了么？
They're tire tracks. That's the entrance.
那是轮胎印 这是入口
Mm-hmm. And this shows the depth of the ice that's covering the ground.
这显示了地上冰层的厚度
Now, this is recent water activity.
这是最近水流活动的记录
If we go in there, Stryker could flood the spillway.
如果我们进去，史崔克会往泄洪道放水的
Can you teleport inside?
你能瞬移到里面吗？
No. I have to be able to see where I'm going...
不能我一定要看到要去的地方
otherwise I could wind up inside a wall.
不然可能会困在墙里
I'll go. I have a hunch he'll want me alive.
我去 我感到他不想我死
Wolverine, whoever goes into the dam needs to be able to operate the spillway mechanism.
罗根，进入大坝的人 要能能操作泄洪装置才行
What do you intend to do?
你打算怎么做？
Scratch it with your claws?
用你的爪子抓？
I'll take my chances.
我赌一赌
But I won't.
我可不想
Sir, there's someone coming down the spillway.
长官，有人进入泄洪道了
- I'm flooding it. - Wait.
- 我来把他冲出去 - 等等
Stryker!
史崔克！
Well, look who's come home.
看看，谁回家了？
Move and you're dead.
再动一下你就死定了
The one thing I know better than anyone is my own work.
我自己的杰作谁也不如我了解
Seal the room. Shoot it.
封闭房间，打死他
- Seal the room  - Step away!
- 封闭房间 - 站开
We have a metamorph loose. Could be anybody.
混进来个变形人 有可能伪装成任何人
Anybody? What-
任何人？ 怎么…
Can you override the spillway mechanism?
你能操控泄洪装置吗？
Everything's controlled from inside that room. That's why the doors are so thick.
只能在这房间里控制 所以门才会这么厚
Oh, really? Get some charges! Blow the doors open!
哦，真的么？ 找些炸药，把门炸开
Take out these cameras!
把摄像机打掉
I'm in.
我进来了
- She's good. - You have no idea.
- 她干的不错 - 还有你没见识过的呢
Fire in the hole.
要引爆了
Move, move, move.
快，快
Sergeant, she's opened the spillway doors.
她打开闸门了
- More mutants have entered the base. - How many?
- 又有变种人进来了 - 多少？
We've lost coms. There's some sort of electrical interference-
通讯中断了，电磁干扰
Sergeant Lyman, gather the rest of your men and meet me outside Cerebro.
莱曼中尉，带你的人到 脑波强化器前跟我会合
You carry on. When I come back, I want this door open all the way!
你们接着干 在我回来前，一定要把这门打开
Welcome, Professor.
欢迎你，教授
- Don't leave me alone, please? - You can come inside.
- 请别丢下我 - 你可以进来
Have you found it?
找到了么？
A large portion of energy from the dam has been diverted to this chamber.
大坝的能量有很大一部分汇集到这间房里
- Cerebro. - There it is.
- 脑波强化器 - 就在那
- Can you shut it down from here? - No.
- 你能在这关上它吗？ - 不行
- Come. There's little time.- Not without us.
- 快，没有时间了 - 一起去吧
Oh, my God. The children.
天啊，孩子们
- Kurt, will you come with me? - Yes
- 库尔特，你和我一起去么？ - 好
- Where are they?- They're being held in a containment cell one level down.
- 他们在哪？ - 在下面一层
Stryker. All right...
史崔克！ 史崔克！
we'll get the children and meet you at Cerebro.
我们去救孩子 然后在脑波强化器和你们会合
Okay. I'll try to find Scott and the professor.
我去找斯科特和教授
- Will you be all right without us? - Yeah. I'll be fine.
- 你一个人能行么？ - 没问题
Where's Logan?
罗根去哪了？
He's gone.
他走了
You, set up a perimeter.  Move, move.
你们都守在这
Jason.
詹森
It's time.
是时候了
Time to find our friends.
该找我们的朋友了
Is it time to find our friends?
该去找我们的朋友的时候了
- All of them. - All of them?
- 所有的人 - 所有的人
- All of the mutants. - All the mutants?
- 所有的变种人 - 所有的变种人
- Everywhere. - Everywhere?
- 所有地方的 - 所有地方的
That's right.  Every one of them?
好的 每一个人？
Oh, yes.  Good.
是的 很好
It's time to bring it to an end.
是时候结束了
Make me proud.
要做得完美
Just don't move.
不要动
Kill anyone who approaches... even if it's me.
靠近者，格杀勿论 包括我
Go! I'll take care of him!
快走，我能应付他
This is one lovef's quarrel we cannot get involved in, my dear.
亲爱的，清官难断家务事，我们走
Scott!
斯科特！
Scott?
斯科特？
- Help us! Anybody! - Listen.
- 救命！ - 听
Help! Get us out of here.
救命！救我们出去
- Julie? - Storm.
- 金勃莉？ - 暴风女
Get us out of here! Okay, we're coming.
救我们出去 我们来了
Scott!
斯科特！
Scott, don't do this!
斯科特，住手
Jean, no, no, no. It's okay.
琴，不要紧 没事了
It's okay. It's me.
没事了，是我
- Scott. - I'm so sorry.
- 斯科特 - 真对不起
- I thought I'd lost you. - Oh, God.
- 我还以为你死了 - 哦，上帝
I'm so sorry. I could see you, but I couldn't stop myself.
我真抱歉 我看到是你，但就是控制不了自己
- I tried. I'm sorry. - I love you so much.
- 我尽力了 对不起 - 我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
- My leg. - Okay, easy. Easy.
- 我的腿 - 放松
Scott...
斯科特
something's wrong.
情况不妙
My God. No!
我的天呀 不
Have you found the mutants yet? Have you found all ofthem?
你找到变种人了么？ 你找到所有变种人了么？
I'm trying. There are so many of them.
我在努力，人太多了
Then concentrate.
那么集中精神
Concentrate.
集中精神
The tricky thing about adamantium is...
成釉细胞有个怪异特性
that if you ever manage to process...
如果你令它控制在
its raw, liquid form, you gotta keep it that way.
原始液体形态 你就得设法让它保持这种状态
Keep it hot.
保持高温
Because once the metal cools, it's indestructible.
因为它一旦冷却 就将坚不可摧
But you already know that.
但这你已经知道了
I used to thinkyou were one of a kind, Wolverine.
我曾认为你是独一无二的，狼人
I was wrong.
我错了
Holy shit.
哦，天呀
That's it.
我受不了了
Whoa. Where do you think you're going?
你要去哪？
I'm sick of this kid's table shit. I'm going in there.
我等够了，我要进去
John, they told us to stay here.
约翰，他们让我们呆在这
You always do as you're told?
你难道永远都这么听话？
Find all the mutants.
找到所有的变种人
Find them.
所有的，找到他们
Find all the mutants. Find them all. Each one. All of them.
找到所有的变种人 每个角落，每个人，所有的人
Good.  Kill them.
然后杀死他们
Concentrate. Concentrate harder.
集中精神，再集中
Now, find them all. Find all the mutants.
现在去找他们,找到所有的变种人
You, concentrate harder.
再集中，找到每个人
Kill them. Kill them all.
杀死他们 把他们全部杀死
Kill them.
杀死他们
Cerebro.
脑波强化器
We're too late.
时间不够了
Eric, hurry!
艾瑞克，快点
That's strange.
奇怪
How does it look from there, Charles?
从那看起来怎么样？查尔斯？
Still fighting the good fight?
还在打正义之战？
From here, it doesn't look like they're playing by your rules.
从现在起 他们好像不再按我们的规则来了
Maybe it's time to play by theirs.
也许该按他们的规则来了
There's been a change of plan.
计划变了
Good-bye, Charles.
再见，查尔斯
There's been a change of plans.
计划变了
Now find them. Find them all, the humans.
现在找到他们 找到所有的人类
Find all the humans. Every one.
找到所有的人类 每一个
How does it feel, bub?
感觉怎么样，杂种？
- Why did you come back? - You cut me open. You took my life!
- 你为什么回来？ - 你把我开膛破肚，夺走了我的生命
You make it sound as if I stole something from you.
说的好像我偷了你东西似的
As I recall, it was you who volunteered for the procedure.
我记得你是自愿参与实验的
- Who am I? - You...
- 我是谁？ - 你…
are just a failed experiment.
只是件失败的试验品
If you really knew about your past...
如果你真知道你的过去
what kind of person you were...
你是个什么样的人
the work we did togethet-
我们曾经一起干的勾当
People don't change, Wolverine.
人不会变的，狼人
You were an animal then. You're an animal now.
你过去是禽兽，现在也是
I just gave you claws.
我只是给了你利爪
What the hell is that? What is it?
出什么事了？ 到底怎么了？
The dam's ruptured. It's gonna flood water into the spillway.
大坝裂开了 水会涌进泄洪道
It's trying to relieve the pressure. It's too late.
我试过释放压力 但太晚了
In a few minutes, we'll all be underwater.
再过几分钟 我们都会被淹没
Come with me, and I'll tell you everything you want to know.
跟我来 你想知道什么我都告诉你
You can't help your friends. They're as good as dead, Wolverine.
你帮不了你的朋友 他们死定了，狼人
You're a survivor, always have been.
你是幸存者 一直都是
Oh, I thought I was just an animal... with claws.
我曾认为自己 只是头长着利爪的野兽
If we die, you die.
我们死了 你也别想活着
There are no answers that way, Wolverine!
在那边你是找不到答案的，狼人
Find all the humans. Every one. Find them.
找到所有的人类 每一个人
Find all the humans. Find them all.
找到所有的人类，每一个，杀死他们
- What is this? - Cerebro.
- 这是什么？ - 脑波强化器
Storm.
暴风女
- Jean. Are you okay? - Yeah. I'm fine.
- 琴，你没事吧？ - 我很好
What's happening?
怎么了？
Professor's still in there... with another mutant.
教授和一个变种人在里面
He's trapped in some kind of illusion.
他陷入了某种幻觉
Oh, my God.
哦，天呐
Magneto's reversed Cerebro. It's not targeting mutants anymore.
上帝脑波强化器被逆置了 这回目标不是变种人了
-  Who is it targeting? - Everyone else.
- 那是谁？ - 人类
Impossible.
不可能
- Everybody stand back. - Scott, no. His mind is connected to Cerebro.
- 都退后 - 不，他现在连在脑波强化器上
Opening the door could kill him and everyone his mind is linked to.
打开门会杀死他 和所有跟他思维相连的人
Wait. Kurt, I need you to take me inside.
等等，克特，我需要你把我送进去
- Storm, who is this guy? Who are you? - My name is Kurt Wagner...
- 这家伙是谁？你是谁？ - 我是克特 瓦格纳
- but in the Munich circus - He's a teleporter.
- 来自马戏团 - 他会瞬间移动
I told you, if I can't see where I'm going.
我说过，如果看不到要去的地方
I have faith in you.
我对你有信心
Don't believe anything you see in there.
在那里看到任何事都别相信
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.
天父，愿荣耀属于你
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on Earth.
天国即将降临 人间
As it is in heaven.
犹如天堂
Hello.
你好
What are you looking for?
你在找什么？
Professor, can you hear me?
教授，你能听见么？
- You've got to stop Cerebro now. - Who are you talking to?
- 你得马上停止脑波强化器 - 你在和谁说话？
No. Don't move.
不要动
But she's just a little girl.
她不过是个小女孩
No, she's not.
不，她不是
I've got my eyes on you.
我已经注意到你了
Mr. Stryker.
史崔克先生
Funny, we keep running into each other.
真有趣，总是碰到你
Mark my words, it'll never happen again.
我保证这不会再发生了
Kurt, it's about to get very cold in here.
克特，这里将变得很冷
I'm not going anywhere.
我会呆着的
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Find all the humans. Kill them.
找到所有人类 杀掉他们
Every single one. Find all the humans.
每一个人 找到所有人类
Focus. Focus. Find all the humans.
集中精神 找到所有人类
Stop it!
住手！
Jason. He's going to be so angry at me.
詹森 他会生我气的
Logan. Logan, where are you?
罗根，你在哪？
We have to get out through the spillway.
我们必须穿过泄洪道
You don't want to go that way. Trust me.
不要走那条路，相信我
Come on. There's another way out of here.
有另一条路出去
The helicopter was right here!
直升机刚才就在这里
I will take him. Okay.
我来抱他
It's okay, Rogue. It's okay. You can let go, honey.
没事，罗杰 你可以放手了，亲爱的
- Let go. - Go. I'll be fine.
- 放手 - 放心  我没事的
- You sure? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 对
Who has the answers, Wolverine?
谁才知道答案,狼人？
Those people?
那些人？
That creature in your arms?
你抱着的那些？
Huh?
啊？
I'll take my chances with him.
我愿意和他一起冒险
One day, someone will finish what I've started, Wolverine!
总有一天，会有人会完成我的工作，狼人
One day!
总有一天
Scott, we've got to get to Washington.
我们要去华盛顿
I fear this has gone beyond Alkali Lake.
这恐怕已不仅是亚克利湖的问题了
Bobby. I got 'im.
我抓住他了
You okay?
你没事吧？
I am now.
现在没事了
- What's wrong? - Vertical thrusters are off line.
- 出什么问题了？ - 推进器坏了
- So fix 'em. - I'm trying.
- 那快修啊 - 我试试看
- Has anyone seen John? - Pyro?
- 有人看到约翰了吗？ - 火人？
Where the hell is he?
他在哪？
He's with Magneto.
他和万磁王在一起
-  Come on! -  Oh, no, we've lost the power.
- 快点 - 哦，不 我们失去了动力
Storm, we need some kind ofexternal power.
斯科特,我们需要一些外力推动
- Jean? - Wait. Where isJean?
- 琴？ - 等等 琴在哪？
She's outside.
她在外面
No, we're not leaving! Lower the ramp!
我们不能走 放下舷梯
Storm, lower it!
暴风女,放舷梯
I can't.
放不了
She's controlling the jet.
她在控制飞机
- You, get her, now! - She's not letting me.
- 你马上去救她 - 她不让我去
Damn it!
该死
I know what I'm doing.
我清楚我在做什么
- This is... - the only way.
- 这是… - 唯一的办法
Jean, listen to me.
琴 听我说
- Don't do this. - Good-bye.
- 不要这样 - 再见
-  Oh, no! No! - No! No!
- 不！不！ - 不！
She's gone.
她死了
- She's gone. - Don't you say that!
- 她死了 - 不要那样说
- We gotta go back. - She's gone.
- 我们要回去 - 她死了
No! No.
没有！没有
She's gone. She's gone. She's-
她死了 她死了
She's gone.
她死了
The Lord is my shepherd. I shall not want.
上帝是我的牧羊人
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures.
他让我能躺在如茵的绿地上
Yea, though I walk through the valley ofthe shadow ofthe death...
虽然我走过死亡的幽谷
I will fear no evil...
我无惧邪恶
for thou art with me.
因为主与我同在
Today I've been given an opportunity to shed light on recent occurrences...
今天我将就最近
from the attack that ended in this office.
椭圆办公室袭击事件…
- Good morning. - to the unexplained phenomenon that swept the Earth...
- 早上好 - 到横扫全球的各种几乎彻底
nearly annihilating ourway of life. Good morning, Mr. President.
湮灭我们生活方式的奇怪现象
Do we like this word "annihilating"?
“彻底湮灭”这个词好么？
Good morning.
早上好
Good morning, Mr. President.
早上好，总统先生
Thankyou.
谢谢
Mr. President, we're live in five, four, three, two
总统先生，马上开始直播… 五，四，三，二…
My fellow Americans, in this time ofadversity...
我的美国同胞们，在这逆境之中
we are being offered a moment...
我们迎来了关键时刻
a moment to recognize a growing threat within our own population...
此时我们要认清 在我们当中逐渐增长的威胁
and take a unique role in the shape of human events.
并在人类历史上扮演一个独特角色
Did we just lose the feed? Are we still live?
广播中断了吗？还在直播吗？
Good morning, Mr. President.
早上好，总统先生
Please, don't be alarmed. We're not going to harm anyone.
别紧张 我们不会伤害任何人
- Who are you people? - We're mutants.
- 你们是谁？ - 我们是变种人
My name is Charles Xavier. Please, sit down.
我叫查尔斯 泽维尔 请坐
- I'd rather stand. - Rogue.
- 我宁愿站着 - 罗杰
These files were taken from the private offices ofWilliam Stryker.
这些文件是在威廉 史崔克的 私人办公室找到的
How did you get this?
你们怎么拿到的？
Well, let's just say I know a little girl who can walk through walls.
就当我认识 一个会穿墙的小姑娘吧
- I've never seen this information. - I know.
- 我从没见过这些资料 - 我知道
Then you also know I don't respond well to threats.
你也知道我不会在威逼下谈判
Mr. President, this is not a threat. This is an opportunity.
总统先生 这不是威逼 这是个机会
There are forces in this world, both mutant and human alike...
世界上的人类和变种人
who believe that a war is coming.
都有一部分相信战争即将来临
You will see from those files that some have already tried to start one...
这些文件可以说明
and there have been casualties.
已经有人在挑起争端
Losses on both sides.
我们双方都有损伤
Mr. President...
总统先生
what you were about to tell the world is true, this is a moment.
你要对全世界说的话是真的 现在是关键时刻
A moment to repeat the mistakes of the past...
是重复过去的错误
or to work together for a better future.
还是携手开创美好未来
We're here to stay, Mr. President. The next move is yours.
我们会留下来的，总统先生 下面看你的了
We'll be watching.
我们拭目以待
Mr. President.
总统先生？
even when Jean was a student...
琴即使在学生时代
she was always hesitant about her powers.
也始终对自己的能力半信半疑
Always looking to others.
她总是看着别人
Feeling that in some way she was left behind.
觉得自己在某些方面 被抛弃了
Do you think-
我们当时
Could we have done more to save her?
可不可能做点什么来救她？
In the past, she may have let us.
在过去，她可能会让我们救她
There had to be another way.
一定另有办法的
Why did she leave the plane?
她为什么要离开飞机？
Because she made a choice.
因为她已做抉择
Yes, come on in.
请进
Listen, she did make a choice.
听着 她确实已做抉择
It was you.
就是你
Professor?
教授？
Is everything all right?
一切都顺利么？
Yes, I think it will be.
是的，我想会的
Now, tell me, have any of you read a book...
大家有没有谁读过这本小说？
by an English novelist named T.H. White...
英国作家TH怀特写的
callled The Once and Future King?
叫《永恒之王》的书
No? Well-
没有？
Mutation.
变异
It is the key to our evolution.
它是我们进化的关键
It is how we have evolved from a single-celled organism...
变异使我们从单细胞生物
into the dominant species on the planet.
进化成地球上的统治物种
This process is slow...
这个过程非常缓慢
normally taking thousands and thousands of years.
通常要花千万年的时间
But every few hundred millennia...
但每几十万年进化过程都会发生跃进